Paulo José da Costa Serrano

PauloJSerrano@gmail.com

Mechanical Engineer and Designer

Graduated with a degree in Mechanical Engineering, I have worked in the oil and gas industry since 2009. First as a Safety Instructor and later as a Designer in the subsea well equipment field. Currently looking for a position as a Mechanical Design Engineer or similar within a company that offers advancement opportunities for dedicated employees. I am a permanent resident of Canada and Brazil and do not need any additional visas for employment within these countries. Some areas I have experience with include:

- Maintenance plan scope definition
- Non-Conformance Report response
- Application of Lean Manufacturing concepts
- Client technical inquiry response
- Technical proposal writeup and execution
- Creation and revision of technical drawings
- Incident Analysis; 8D, FMECA, etc.
- BOM creation and Engineering Changes
- Structural and lifting calculations
- Native English & Portuguese

Professional Experience

Aker Solutions 2017 - Current

Designer & Mechanical Engineer

Member of the Product Engineering team in Aker's Services site in Brazil. Direct contact with onshore manufacturing environment, offshore technical operations and contracts and tender departments. Responsible for the **creation and revision of technical drawings** for subsea equipment and tools as well as the issuing of **technical proposals** and purchase **specifications for tender**. Knowledge and experience working with subsea structures and equipment.

Main Contributions

- Member of the **Digitalization** task force. Implementation of a database program that increased the efficiency and **standardization** of Damage Reports issued by the Industrial Engineering department, reducing rework and cutting costs.
- Contributed to the reduction of the non-conformance indicators through the proper planning and prioritization of the revision of documents that are critical for manufacturing.

Aker Solutions do Brasil

2015 - 2017

Engineering Intern

Member of the Maintenance Engineering team, responsible for the issuing of Damage Reports and delineating the scope of repair for submarine tools and equipment, dealing directly with the contracts department to answer technical queries.

Revelo Electric 2014 - 2014

Engineering Intern

Summer intern at Toronto start-up dedicated to the design of personal electric vehicles that feature innovation and superior design. My responsibilities included product prototyping, customer relations, order fulfillment, and participation in key business strategy meetings and decision-making processes.

Sampling Planejamento

2009 - 2013

Safety Instructor

Initially hired as simultaneous language interpreter for workplace safety courses, eventually promoted to safety instructor. Instructed domestic and international oilfield workers on good safety practices and local laws and regulations.

Education

Federal University of Rio de Janeiro

2011 - 2016

Mechanical Engineering

Graduated with a degree in Mechanical Engineering at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro. Involved in scientific outreach programs. Elected class Orator for the Mechanical, Industrial and Civil Engineering graduating classes in 2016.

University of Toronto

2014 - 2014

Mechanical Engineering [Exchange Program]

Brazilian government international scholarship recipient, sent to the University of Toronto as a part of a program to improve the international relationships between universities and companies in Brazil and abroad.

Professional Skills

- Native English and Portuguese speaker. Advanced Spanish. Basic French.
- Professional experience using AutoCAD, Solidworks, Excel (VBA), Word etc.
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&T), API 6A, API 17D, API 17G, etc.
- Knowledge and experience in the implementation of Six Sigma, Lean Manufacturing, 5S and other quality management tools.
- Leadership skills and specific training on leadership styles for engineers.

References

Joel Fonseca – Engineering Specialist, Aker Solutions: +55 (21) 98118-5727

Mary Chong - VP of Business Development, Revelo Electric: +1 (416) 434-0376